KERI MEDEIROS | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Los Angeles, CA | 774-526-8159 | kerimedeiros@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer skilled in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Node.js, and PostgreSQL with a prior career in digital marketing, advertising technology, and media operations. Experience contributing to the growth and operational scale of media companies and technology platforms with hundreds of millions of users worldwide.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, Knex.js

Other: Test-Driven Development (Mocha, Chai, Jest), Vercel, Render, Git/GitHub, Node Package Manager, Salesforce, Visual Studio Code, Project Management Systems (Jira, Trello, Basecamp), Google Ad Manager

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Restaurant Reservation Application | Thinkful | Link

03/2023

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented React Router and Express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and Knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Technology: React, Node is, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL, and Git.

Movie Database Application | Thinkful | Link

01/2023

- Assembled the backend of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and viewing theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.is, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL, and Git.

Study Tool Application | Thinkful | Link

10/2022

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and flashcards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow users to create, read, update and delete.
- Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML, CSS, and Git.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Google (YouTube)

Los Angeles, CA

04/2019 - 04/2022

Digital Media Operations Manager

- Managed ad-supported and subscription video content launch operations (Linear, VOD, and Live Streams) across YouTube TV and YouTube.com for major entertainment studios and music record label partners.
- Oversaw a team of contractors responsible for media file delivery processing, QA, and technical troubleshooting required to onboard high-profile partners onto the YouTube content ingestion pipeline.
- Supported workflow automation efforts by establishing new operational processes and developing proprietary digital media management software in partnership with global Product and Engineering teams.

Netflix

San Francisco, CA / Los Angeles, CA

Program Manager, Global Marketing Operations

03/2018 - 04/2019

- Facilitated internal tooling feature requests from the Global Marketing Operations team and collaborated with Product Management and Engineering teams to develop a quarterly product roadmap for in-house marketing tooling solutions, enabling global scale and improving marketing campaign launch efficiency.
- Led trainings and conducted user acceptance tests for new product feature releases for internal marketing technology tools used by 500+ users across the Netflix Global Marketing Operations org.
- Performed comprehensive ad software testing and validation to ensure seamless integration of internal advertising technology tools with technology partners such as Google, YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter.

Global Ad Operations Lead

02/2016 - 03/2018

- Managed end-to-end digital advertising operations for global member acquisition marketing efforts, including ad creative production, trafficking, quality assurance, and troubleshooting for digital marketing and paid social campaigns with allocated media budgets exceeding \$500 million+.
- Worked closely with Product and Engineering teams to develop proprietary marketing technology tools and software used to successfully reduce turnaround time from creative production to campaign launch.
- Led hiring efforts for the expansion of the global ad operations team, onboarded new hires, and established new operational workflows to support global digital marketing campaign launch efforts.

DataXu (acquired by Roku)

Boston, MA

Ad Operations Team Lead

09/2015 - 02/2016

- Launched and optimized cross-platform digital marketing campaigns using in-house ad technology software to support 50+ clients with programmatic marketing budgets exceeding \$10MM+.
- Served as escalation point of contact for ad creative technical issues and ad exchange compliance issues, partnering closely with the Support Engineering team to ensure timely resolution of client escalations.
- Managed outsourced operations with offshore vendor teams and onboarded new hires.

Ad Operations Specialist

01/2014 - 09/2015

- Resolved all client requests received through an internal Salesforce ticketing system within defined service level agreements (SLAs), including tasks related to ad creative trafficking, ad quality assurance review, and technical troubleshooting for marketing campaigns using DataXu's ad technology software.
- Oversaw third-party ad server software certification processes and effectively integrated DataXu's ad technology stack with more than 30 ad technology partners, including Google, Facebook, and Yahoo.

Boston Globe Media Boston, MA

Digital Ad Operations Coordinator

06/2012 - 05/2013

- Managed the launch and optimization of digital advertising campaigns across all Boston Globe Media affiliated websites such as Boston.com and BostonGlobe.com, reaching millions of site visitors each month.
- Led the testing and rollout of innovative display media and video ad units (HTML, JS, and XML formats).

Audacy, Inc. (formerly Entercom Communications)

Boston, MA

Digital Ad Operations Coordinator

11/2010 - 06/2012

- Partnered with digital producers to develop and launch display banner ads (HTML and JS formats), promotional emails, and audio/video ads for digital advertising campaigns across multiple New England commercial radio station websites and their associated internet radio streaming apps.
- Served as primary point of contact for Sales and Account Management teams in regards to digital ad specifications, website ad inventory availability, and technical requirements for ad campaign launches.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online

Certificate, Software Engineering Program

07/2022 - 03/2023

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

Emerson College
Bachelor of Science, Marketing

Boston, MA

05/2010